Sidharth

Developer @ Innovation labs

Innovative tech mind with 1.6 years of experience working as a computer programmer. Capable of working with a variety of technology and software solutions, and managing databases. Valuable team member who has experience diagnosing problems and developing solutions. Talented person with unique ideas and a history of successful contributions in the field.

♥ Shasta Nilayam, km Challa,
Eduppukulam(Po) Palakkad, Kerala
 6238471816 ☑ sidharthe38943@gmail.com Pincode 678556 ☑ Indian
 07/07/1999 ♥ Single

EDUCATION

VIb Janakiammal College of Arts and Science

BCA

17/07/2017 - 21/09/2020

Grade - 78% Coimbatore

Bachelor in Computer Application (BCA) is an undergraduate degree course in computer applications. The duration of the course is 3 years and divided into 6 semesters. It comprises of the subjects like database, networking, data structure, core programming languages like 'C' and 'java'.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SRF

TCS

18/01/2021 - 01/06/2022

Chennai

Site reliability engineers sit at the crossroads of traditional IT and software development. SRE teams are made up of software engineers who build and

implement software to improve the reliability of their systems

Developer

TCS

06/06/2022 - Present

chennai

Developer at TCS innovation lab .TCS has a global network of innovation labs, classified as technology labs, academic alliance labs and domain labs. The labs create differentiators and build innovation capabilities for TCS's businesses, helping its customers with innovation across different time zones.

PROJECTS

1. Host override testing

Tool is created as part of SRE automation . The tool is created using c# and selenium which will check the overall response time of the web page and will calculate the performance of the web site.

Technology used: asp.net and c#

2. Python voice assistant bot

A personal assistant using python which can perform various actions based on voice commands like sending email, surfing on web, mathematical calculation, playing music, opening files, etc

Technology used: Python 3.Daily Expense Tracker

"DAILY EXPENSE TRACKER" is a project which pro-

poses to form a process that can help to store and retrieve details regarding the expense of a person or an organization. My project has several

modules which are, login Dashboard. It can generate various reports as per requirements. It follows the two- tier architecture with front-end php and back-end SQL Server. My project is capable of generating exepense report based on months, year aswell as days

Technology used:PHP, mysql

4.Individual household electric power consumption Data Set Performed various techniques in data set and created model

- Data exploration and analysis.
- Data Visualization .
- Regression and Time series analysis.
- · Frequency Domain Analysis.

Technology used: Python

5. Mask detection

A deep learning based model for detecting masks over faces in public place to curtail community spread of Coronavirus is presented. The proposed model efficiently handles varying kinds of occlusions in dense situation by making use of ensemble of single and two stage detectors. The ensemble approach not only helps in achieving high accuracy but also improves detection speed considerably. The model is 98.2% accurate at mask detection with averageinference times of 0.05 seconds per image

Technology used: Python

6.SL triage tool

This project is created as part of SRE automation. The tool is created using asp.net. The functionality of tool is to fetch required details of member from database and api. This details will be further used to validate overall account setup and will display the result.

Technology used :Asp.net and C#

6.Akaname report genarator

The tool is created aspart of SRE automation. The tool is created to cross verify the data from vendor with data from database. The verified data report will be automatically send to vendor mail.

Technology used: C#

7.Infra predictionrA

The application is created as part of innovation team project. The application motive is predict the snowday tickets count and categorize the tickets by training the data pulled from Snowday using SARIMA model and deployed the model in application created using django .

Technology used: Django framework and python

SKILLS

Asp.net, C#, Azure, Python, web technologies (HTML,CSS,Js), Vue.js, Data science

LANGUAGES

Malayalam, English, Tamil, Hindi

STRENGTHS

Dedication, Hardworking, Strong Work Ethic, Punctuality, Listening skills, Analytical and Problem Solving Skills

INTERESTS

Software development, Web development, AI/ML